<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Carpentry at the University of Oslo</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Carpentry at the University of Oslo</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https:uio-carpentry.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Carpentry@UiO 2020 Annual Report</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/reports/report_carpentry-uio_2020/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/reports/report_carpentry-uio_2020/</guid><description>Carpentry@UiO 2020 Annual Report # Report written by Naoe Tatara and Annika Rockenberger (both University of Oslo library)
Learner Feedback and Continuous Evaluation # Carpentries survey # In this year, we used the Carpentries pre- and post-workshop survey. Due to the problems described in the next section, we have not yet gotten access to the whole dataset. However, the responses given in 5-Likert scale were mostly positive.
On the other hand, the responses written in free text are summarised in &amp;ldquo;Carpentries-survey-results&amp;rdquo; Sheet in Carpentry@UiO G Suite shared drive, which is accessible only to board members.</description></item><item><title>Oslo useR! Mild introduction to Structural Equation Modeling</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2020-06-03-user/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2020-06-03-user/</guid><description>Date: Tuesday, 3rd June 2020 Time: 17:00 Place: IFI Building, University of Oslo What we&amp;rsquo;ll do # When working with data, we often want to create models to predict future events, but we also want an even deeper understanding of how our data is connected or structured. In this workshop, we will explore the connectedness of data using using structural equation modeling (SEM) with {lavaan} package.
Stay tuned for updates!</description></item><item><title>Zotero Add-Ons, Extensions, and Plugins</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2020-05-14-workalong/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2020-05-14-workalong/</guid><description>Workalong: Zotero Add-Ons, Extensions, and Plugins # Session leader: Annika Rockenberger
Level: beginner When: Thursday, May 14 Time: 16:00-18:00 Location: Niels Henrik Abels hus Room 209 What&amp;rsquo;s happening?
We meet and together we explore a couple of add-ons, plugins and extensions for Zotero. If you know a cool add-on, please bring it and show us how to use it!
Come with your laptop – it&amp;rsquo;s probably a good idea to have Zotero installed.</description></item><item><title>&lt;Canceled> Workalong - Creating Websites with Jekyll</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2020-04-02-workalong/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2020-04-02-workalong/</guid><description>Session leader: Naoe Tatara
Level: beginner When: 2020-04-16 Time: 16:00-18:00 Location: Niels Henrik Abels hus Room 209 What&amp;rsquo;s happening?
Due to Covid-19 spreading and closed buildings of UiO and unknown level of interest, the session is canceled. It will be held in future, either online or in person, when the situation gets better and there is enough interest.
We meet and together create a website using Jekyll. We will learn a bit about web design and web development.</description></item><item><title>Copernicus Climate Data Store for professionals and students</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2020-03-06-copernicus/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2020-03-06-copernicus/</guid><description>The training is free but attendance to all three events is mandatory.
First webinar: 19th of February, 10:00- 11:15h (local time) - Introduction to the blended training approach Self-paced study and completion of assignments (10 hours) Full day face-to-face event: 6th of March, (Oslo) – Flipped classroom (review your learning), hands-on practical activities, development of a climate change adaptation case study Self-paced study and further elaboration of the climate adaptation case study (8 hours) Final webinar: 27th of March, 10:00-11:30h (local time) - Presentation of case studies, discussion, and questions and answers session The target audiences are</description></item><item><title>Preview of the Data Carpentry - Genomics curriculum</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2020-03-05-preview/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2020-03-05-preview/</guid><description>Session leader: Tina Visnovska
Level: beginner When: 2020-03-05 Time: 16:00-18:00 Location: Niels Henrik Abels hus Room 209 What&amp;rsquo;s happening?
Preview of the Data Carpentry: Genomics Curriculum.</description></item><item><title>Oslo useR! Geospatial data science with R</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2020-02-18-user/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2020-02-18-user/</guid><description>Topic: Geospatial data with R Speaker: Benno Dillinger works as data engineer at the Section for Environmental Data Science at the Norwegian Institute for Water Research. Date: Tuesday, 18 February 2020 Time: 17:00 Place: Teknologihuset What we&amp;rsquo;ll do # R has advanced capabilities for managing spatial data and it provides unparalleled opportunities for managing, visualizing and analyzing such data.
In this meetup we will learn about R packages {sf} and {stars}, commonly used for manipulating feature and gridded data.</description></item><item><title>Oslo useR! Machine Learning in R? Easier than you think</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2020-01-21-user/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2020-01-21-user/</guid><description>Topic: Machine Learning in R? Easier than you think! Speaker: Bethan Cropp (Amesto NextBridge) Date: Tuesday, 21 January 2020 Time: 17:00 Place: Teknologihuset What we&amp;rsquo;ll do # We welcome the new year with an exciting presentation by Bethan Cropp, who will talk about her experience with Machine Learning and R!
Make sure not to miss it!
Description # Getting started with Keras in R is not difficult, but it has a few quirks.</description></item><item><title>Planning Meeting for the Spring Term 2020</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2020-01-16-admin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2020-01-16-admin/</guid><description>Session leader: Annika Rockenberger
Level: beginner When: 2020-01-16 Time: 16:00-18:00 Location: Niels Henrik Abels hus Room 209 What&amp;rsquo;s happening?
We meet and plan the StudyGroup activities for the spring term 2020. Everyone is welcome, we are looking for suggestions from all of our members. The StudyGroup will meet every other week until the end of May.
To make suggestions prior to the meeting, you can create an Issue and suggest a date that suits you.</description></item><item><title>Julefest - End of the Year Party</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-12-12-julefest/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-12-12-julefest/</guid><description>Session leader: Annika Rockenberger
Topic: Julefest - End of the Year Party
Who: all Carpentries@UiO community members: instructors, helpers, learners, support staff When: 12nd December 2019 Time: 16:00-20:00 Location: Niels Henrik Abels hus Room 209 Julefest # The temperatures have already dropped below 0°C and friends and colleagues have started booking their annual end-of-the-year-travels. Which means it is about time to prepare for a decent Julefest with the Carpentry@UiO community!</description></item><item><title>Carpentry@UiO 2019 Annual Report</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/reports/report_carpentry-uio_2019/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/reports/report_carpentry-uio_2019/</guid><description>Carpentry@UiO 2019 Annual Report # Learner Feedback and Continuous Evaluation # Spring Term 2019 # See the detailed report for the spring term 2019 Report Spring 2019 Fall Term 2019 # See the detailed report for 2019 incl. the feedback for the fall term 2019 Workshops # Programming with Python (novices) - Feb 8, 2019 Introduction to Version Control with Git (novices) - Feb 15, 2019 Git in Practice (intermediate) - Feb 27, 2019 Data Analysis and Visualisation in R for Ecologists - Mar 8, 2019 Unix Shell (novices) - Apr 24, 2019 Data Analysis and Visualisation in R for Ecologists - May 15, 2019 Introduction to R with Tidyverse (pt.</description></item><item><title>Carpentries-Workshops 2019 - Summary Of Learners' Feedback</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/reports/summary_feedback_uio-carpentry_2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/reports/summary_feedback_uio-carpentry_2019/</guid><description>Carpentries-Workshops 2019 &amp;ndash; Summary Of Learners&amp;rsquo; Feedback # Data and Data Analysis # After every workshop taught by Carpentry@UiO, a post-workshop feedback survey is sent out to participants, circa one-two weeks after the workshop. The responses are collected in Nettskjema. For this report, I have downloaded the data from the main Nettkjema survey as well as the data from two survey forms that were created for the GitHub workshop in September 2019 and the Databases and SQL workshop in October 2019.</description></item><item><title>Instructor development and discussion on how to teach</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-11-21-instructors/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-11-21-instructors/</guid><description>Session leader: Karin Lagesen
Topic: Instructor development and discussion on how to teach
Who: all Carpentries@UiO instructors When: 21st November 2019 Time: 16:00-18:00 Location: Niels Henrik Abels hus Room 209</description></item><item><title>Report of the Instructor Status Survey 2019</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/reports/report_instructor-status-survey_2019-11-07/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/reports/report_instructor-status-survey_2019-11-07/</guid><description>Report of the Instructor Status Survey 2019 # Author: Annika Rockenberger Date: Nov 7, 2019
Introduction # Data Collection # An online survey was created using Nettskjema (University of Oslo web-tool for surveys). The questions asked can be found in the survey document. The survey was then send to the organizers mailing list on Oct 10. A reminder to participate in the survey was sent out to the same list on Oct 16 and Nov 06.</description></item><item><title>Hackathon</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-10-17-tagathon/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-10-17-tagathon/</guid><description>Session leader: Annika Rockenberger
Topic: Preparing something cool for the Carpentries Tagathon in Week 44
Hackathon - Tagathon # The Carpentries are inviting to a community initative in week 44 called &amp;ldquo;Hacktoberfest&amp;rdquo;. It is about tagging the many blog posts on the three Carpentries websites: Software Carpentry, Data Carpentry, and Library Carpentry. The aim is to make the posts more findable by assigning topics.
Combining the skills taught in The Carpentries with the power of Digital Humanities, this StudyGroup will attempt to create a set of tags for the blog posts based on computational text analysis.</description></item><item><title>Survey – Carpentry@UiO Instructor Status Quo</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/reports/survey_instructor-status_2019-09-26/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/reports/survey_instructor-status_2019-09-26/</guid><description>Survey – Carpentry@UiO Instructor Status Quo # Introduction and Purpose # Dear fellow Carpenter!
The Carpentry@UiO community is alive and well – a new team of coordinators from the University Library together with the Interim Board are working hard to support you in teaching workshops in the Carpentries spirit.
In order to gain a better and more up-to-date overview of who we are as a community, the Interim Board and the University Library have created a short survey about the status quo of our instructors.</description></item><item><title>Voila python package</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-09-26-voila/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-09-26-voila/</guid><description>Session leader: Anne Fouilloux
Rendering of live Jupyter notebooks with interactive widgets.
Voila serves live Jupyter notebook including Jupyter interactive widgets.
Unlike the usual HTML-converted notebooks, each user connecting to the Voila tornado application gets a dedicated Jupyter kernel which can execute the callbacks to changes in Jupyter interactive widgets.
During this two hour session, we plan to explore the voila package and learn how to use it. The idea is to understand if it is useful for our researchers.</description></item><item><title>Lesson Development</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-09-19-lessondev/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-09-19-lessondev/</guid><description>Session leader: Annika Rockenberger
Topic: Good Enough Practices in Scientific Computing
Picking up from where we left on 5th September 2019, we continue developing a lesson for a half-day workshop based on the article by Wilson et al. &amp;ldquo;Good Enough Practices in Scientific Computing&amp;rdquo; (2017). The article focuses not so much on computing but general digital literacy and good routines.
Join if you are interested in lesson development, digital literacy, and how to improve our daily data and computational habits!</description></item><item><title>Instructor development and discussion on how to teach</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-09-12-instructors/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-09-12-instructors/</guid><description>Session leader: Karin Lagesen
Topic: Instructor development and discussion on how to teach
Who: all Carpentries@UiO instructors When: 12nd September 2019 Time: 16:00-18:00 Location: Niels Henrik Abels hus Room 209</description></item><item><title>Book Club</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-09-05-bookclub/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-09-05-bookclub/</guid><description>Session leader: Annika Rockenberger
Topic: Good Enough Practices in Scientific Computing
We are reading the article &amp;ldquo;Good Enough Practices in Scientific Computing&amp;rdquo; by Greg Wilson et al.
https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1005510
Come and discuss the article with us!
We want to create a Carpentries-style, half-day workshop based on the article, to be piloted in the fall semester here at UiO. Please bring the text &amp;amp; your laptop: we will work together brainstorming how to develop a lesson based on the contents of the article, and start creating a repository for the workshop development using the Carpentries lesson template.</description></item><item><title>Preview lesson on Open Science</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-08-29-osip/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-08-29-osip/</guid><description>Session leader: Anne Fouilloux
Walk-through of the pre-prepared lesson (see https://coderefinery.github.io/osip/) to give feedback. This lesson will be taught at the 2019 Eurotech Summer School OPEN SCIENCE IN PRACTICE as a two-hour workshop.
The plan is also to teach it at UiO next semester or during the Research Bazaar.
Come and discuss with us how we can improve the lesson.
Feedback is welcome!
Who: anyone interested in Open Science When: 29th August 2019 Time: 16:00-18:00 Location: Niels Henrik Abels hus Room 209</description></item><item><title>StudyGroup Planning</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-08-22-planning/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-08-22-planning/</guid><description>Session leader: Annika Rockenberger
We are having a meeting to plan all our future events for Autumn 2019.
Come and tell us what events you would be interested to learn or to teach.
Level: all When: 22nd August 2019 Time: 16:00-18:00 Location: Niels Henrik Abels hus Room 209</description></item><item><title>Carpentries-Workshops Spring 2019 -- Summary Of Learners' Feedback</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/reports/summary_feedback_carpentries_spring_2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/reports/summary_feedback_carpentries_spring_2019/</guid><description>Carpentries-Workshops Spring 2019 &amp;ndash; Summary Of Learners&amp;rsquo; Feedback # Workshops # Workshops We Taught # Python (novices) - Feb 8, 2019 Intro to Git (novices) - Feb 15, 2019 Git in Practice (intermediate) - Feb 27, 2019 Data Analysis and Visualisation in R for Ecologists - Mar 8, 2019 Unix Shell (novices) - Apr 24, 2019 Data Analysis and Visualisation in R for Ecologists - May 15, 2019 Introduction to R with Tidyverse (pt.</description></item><item><title>Carpentries, CarpentryConnect Manchester conference 2019</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-06-25-carpentryconnect/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-06-25-carpentryconnect/</guid><description>Join Us At CarpentryConnect Manchester 2019! # Did you see the recent announcement, that registration is now open for the CarpentryConnect Manchester conference? The event is an opportunity for members of The Carpentries’ global community of instructors and anyone else with an interest in helping researchers to improve their computational skills, to get together for a few days to exchange ideas and learn some new things. With an exciting programme (still under development, no spoilers!</description></item><item><title>Oslo useR! Group, Workshop Straightforward introduction to mixed models</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-06-05-user/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-06-05-user/</guid><description>Session leader: Dmytro P. and Athanasia Monika M.
In this workshop we will be exploring how to use linear mixed models when we have data that repeats over time. These kinds of models are often used in longitudinal studies or with time series data. They are powerful as the used maximum likelihood approximations rather than least squares, meaning they can better handle missing data, and competing models can be compared directly.</description></item><item><title>CodeRefinery, CodeRefinery workshop in Oslo</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-06-03-coderefinery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-06-03-coderefinery/</guid><description>Session leader: Radovan Bast, Anne Fouilloux and Sabry Razick.
Course goals # The aim of this course is to demonstrate to and familiarize the workshop participants with best practices and tools in modern research software development. The main focus is on professional tools for efficiently developing and maintaining research software. Since most research code is developed in a collaborative setting, we will discuss tools and workflows which facilitate this process. Most of the content is also relevant to a single developer.</description></item><item><title>Work along session on image processing in R</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-05-24-workalong/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-05-24-workalong/</guid><description>Session leader: Ana Costa
In this session you will learn image processing in R.
Bring your laptop if you want to try it out!
When: 24th May 2019, 14h-16h Location: Vilhelm Bjerknes&amp;rsquo; hus, room 123 Who: everybody willing to learn about image processing</description></item><item><title>use R! group, Investing with R</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-05-08-user/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-05-08-user/</guid><description>Session leader: Dmytro Perepolkin and Lars Nygaard
Most investors still invest through expensive traditional active funds although studies clearly show that cheap index funds do better over time and, modern Nobel-prize winning research shows there are fully automated strategies, or so-called factor-based strategies, that do even better.
R is today one of the best languages to do prototyping for quantitative investment analysis. Lars will give an introduction on implementing a simple quantitative investing strategy using packages such as quantmod, xts.</description></item><item><title>use R! group, Building websites in R, step-by-step introduction to blogdown</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-04-02-user/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-04-02-user/</guid><description>Session leader: Dmytro Perepolkin and Andrea Chi Zhang
A personal website or blog is a great place to record, share and communicate your thoughts and learning process, however the whole procedure might seem complex to those without relevant experience. An R package developed by Yihui Xie, blogdown, makes it easy to build a website using R Markdown and Hugo. Andrea will talk about what is blogdown and why you should use it, and walk you through the basic steps to publish (for free!</description></item><item><title>RLadies Oslo, Bayesian methods for rank and preference data with Valeria Vitelli</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-03-18-rladies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-03-18-rladies/</guid><description>Session leader: Valeria Vitelli, Lene Norderhaug D., Aurora V., Athanasia Monika Mowinckel, Isabelle V.
Bayesian methods for rank and preference data - from recommendation systems to cancer genomics
Ranking items is crucial for collecting information about preferences in many areas, from marketing to politics. The interest often lies both in producing estimates of the consensus ranking of the items, which is shared among users, and in learning individualized preferences of the users, useful for providing personalized recommendations.</description></item><item><title>use R! group - Workshop- Introduction to Automatic and Scalable Machine Learning with H2O in R</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-03-05-user/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-03-05-user/</guid><description>Session leader: Dmytro Perepolkin
Choosing best model for your machine learning problem may be daunting task. H2O AutoML simplifies the process of setting up the complex machine learning modeling pipelines to just a few lines of code. You will learn how to make your own stacked ensemble in the first 30 min of the workshop. For those who want to stick around for the rest of the evening, we will go a bit deeper into specification of individual models (GLM, GBM, Neural Networks, etc) and understanding of model performance.</description></item><item><title>Do I need my own website as a researcher?</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-03-01-workalong/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-03-01-workalong/</guid><description>Session leader: Annika Rockenberger
During this session, we will look at a couple of examples of personal websites of researchers and other academics. We will discuss the advantages and disadvantages of hosting your own website, of having a website at your research institution or university or using commercial platforms like LinkedIn, ResearchGate, Academia.edu etc. We will also look at alternatives, e.g. creating a professional profile website hosted on GitHub.
The event is open for anyone!</description></item><item><title>Oslo useR! Group, Mild introduction to Rcpp</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-02-06-user/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-02-06-user/</guid><description>Session leader: Dmytro Perepolkin and Øystein Sørensen
Sometimes R code just isn’t fast enough. You’ve used profiling to figure out where your bottlenecks are, and you’ve done everything you can in R, but your code still isn’t fast enough. In this talk you will learn how you can improve performance by rewriting key functions in C++. Rcpp provides a clean, approachable API that lets you write high-performance code with as little friction as possible.</description></item><item><title>Workalong Git without Bash</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-02-06-workalong/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-02-06-workalong/</guid><description>Session leader: Annika Rockenberger
A short work along trying out alternatives to git bash, especially for Windows users.
Bring your laptop. We want to look at editors like Atom, oXygen XML editor, Sublime and others which have git plugins. The goal is to come up with a handy guide on how to make use of git (on Windows) without having to install and run Git Bash, especially if the user doesn&amp;rsquo;t have admin rights.</description></item><item><title>RLadies Oslo, Building shiny dashboards - with Aurora and Lene</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-02-04-rladies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-02-04-rladies/</guid><description>Session leader: Lene Norderhaug D., Aurora V., Athanasia Monika Mowinckel, Isabelle V.
In this workshop, Aurora and Lene will take us through the steps of building a shiny dashboard. We will incrementally build the dashboard, with explanations throughout to help you understand how the components act together.
At the end of the workshop, you should enough basic understanding of shiny to be able to start building your own shiny dashboard.</description></item><item><title>Software surgery session on Python</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-02-01-software-surgery/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-02-01-software-surgery/</guid><description>Session leader: Anne Fouilloux
This is a drop-in session for asking specific problems on Python programming.
Come with your specific problem:
you are stuck with your program and do not understand why it does not work you are unsure about which python package to use for solving a specific problem you have tried to use a Python package but it does not work as you expected. or come and help:</description></item><item><title>Book Club on Teaching Tech together</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-01-18-bookclub/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-01-18-bookclub/</guid><description>Session leader: Anne Fouilloux
You read at least 5 chapters of &amp;ldquo;Teaching Tech together&amp;rdquo; (Greg Wilson) and would like to discuss and share your thoughts about teaching techniques.
We are using https://web.hypothes.is/, an online tool to annotate the web, with anyone, anywhere.
The StudyGroup@UiO share comments at https://hypothes.is/groups/mReaNk2e/studygroup-uio.
online material to learn how to use hypothes.is:
https://web.hypothes.is/quick-start-guide-for-students/ When: 18th January 2019, 14-16h Location: Vilhelm Bjerknes&amp;rsquo; hus, room 123</description></item><item><title>Oslo useR! Group, Prepare to be surprised! Visualizing public data from npd.no</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-01-10-user/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2019-01-10-user/</guid><description>Session leader: Dmytro Perepolkin and Kristijan Bakaric
“Visualization can surprise, but it doesn’t scale. Modeling scales well, but it can’t fundamentally surprise.” – Hadley Wickham.
One of the most important phases in the Data Analysis process is data visualization. It is an inherently human activity which relies on our ability to comprehend visual information and make sense of patterns. However, there’s only so much we can spend in visualizing the data, and regardless how many hours we may decide to put into it, it is never going to be enough.</description></item><item><title>Social coding and open software</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2018-12-14-demo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2018-12-14-demo/</guid><description>Session leader: Anne Fouilloux
During this session, we will present you:
Why software matters in research Why open software How to do open software How to grow a community around your code When: 14th December 2018, 14-16h Location: Niels Henrik Abels hus, room 209</description></item><item><title>use R! group How analysing football data made me fall in love with football again</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2018-12-10-user/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2018-12-10-user/</guid><description>Session leader: Toju Idowu and Dmytro Perepolkin
In this talk, I will show you how I’ve used R to delve deep into how football works. I’ll work through a simple GLM using some of the new tidymodels packages.
About the speaker: Toju is an actuary originally from the UK, living in Oslo. He has been using R for about four years ever since he accidentally discovered it while searching for how to do linear regression in Excel.</description></item><item><title>RLadies Oslo, Topic modelling - what is it, and how does VG use it?</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2018-12-03-rladies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2018-12-03-rladies/</guid><description>Session leader: Athanasia Monika Mowinckel
The next RLadies-Oslo next meetup is set for December 3rd, with the amazing @ZazzValette presenting &amp;ldquo;Topic modelling - what is it, and how does VG use it?”
Topic models (TM) are powerful tools to programmatically uncover textual structure in what otherwise appear to be just plain unstructured text. The applications of TM are many, like content analysis, article search, and personalisation of content. Isabelle Valette will take us through what topic models are, the way the algorithm works, and how VG has been using it inside and outside the newsroom.</description></item><item><title>Work along session on Data Management Plan</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2018-11-30-workalong/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2018-11-30-workalong/</guid><description>Session leader: Michael Heeremans
Everything you need to know to start writing your own Data Management Plan.
You will learn what tools you can use to help you writing your DMP (Data Management Plan) and what is important to address to manage your data efficiently.
When: 30th November 2018, 14-16h Location: Niels Henrik Abels hus, room 209 Who: everybody interested in learning about &amp;ldquo;Data Management Plans&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Statistrikketreff for vaksine (event in Norwegian)</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2018-11-20-statistrikketreff/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2018-11-20-statistrikketreff/</guid><description>Session leader: Kathrine Frey Frøslie
(event in Norwegian)
For to år siden satte statistiker Kathrine Frey Frøslie fart på strikkepinnene og ga seg i kast med den opplagte oppgaven det er å formidle kunnskap om forskning og statistikk gjennom strikkeprosjekter. Smittespredning og vaksinedekning har vært tema for flere elegante ullkreasjoner og gjesteblogginnlegg av førstelektor Tone Fredsvik Gregers ved UiO. På statistrikketreffet får du høre mer om dette, se plagg som viser kritisk vaksinedekning for ulike sykdommer og lære hvordan du kan strikke en lekker vaksinedekningsklut som du kan gi til din yndlingsvaksinemotstander.</description></item><item><title>Work along session on "Automated testing"</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2018-11-09-workalong/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2018-11-09-workalong/</guid><description>Session leader: Gladys Nalvarte
When: 9th November 2018, 14-16h Where: Niels Henrik Abels hus, room 209 Who: everybody willing to learn about &amp;ldquo;pytest&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Oslo useR! Group, Making tidyverse-friendly packages</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2018-11-07-user/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2018-11-07-user/</guid><description>Session leader: Raoul Wolf
Raoul will share his experience from simplifying a workflow by writing an R package; under the restriction of minimal dependencies, while maintaining full compatibility for tidyverse. In his own words: «I was working on a new project and I noticed I was sourcing dozens of functions from multiple scripts. I thought to myself: “I might as well do what everyone is doing and write a package!» Come and join us in learning how to identify the need for a package, strategically plan the process of writing the package, and to keep track on applicability and usability.</description></item><item><title>Demo session on openscience framework</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2018-11-02-demo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2018-11-02-demo/</guid><description>Session leader: Michael Heeremans
Openscience: come and show your openscience framework.
Short coding ligthning demo on openscience. If you wish to show your openscience framework, please contact the organizer (comment this issue).
When: 2nd November 2018, 14-16h Location: Niels Henrik Abels hus, room 209 Who: anyone interested in openscience</description></item><item><title>Co-working session on "Internet of Things (IoT) with Arduino"</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2018-10-26-coworking/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2018-10-26-coworking/</guid><description>Session leader: Annika Rockenberger
Come and meet us for two hours to learn about Internet of Things and work with an Arduino (demos). Annika will bring a couple of Arduino Unos, breadboards, jumper cables, LEDs, resistors, buttons and a selection of sensors (light, distance, temperature, CO2 sensors). We have a take on physical programming with Arduino and micro electronics. It will be fun!
When: 26th October 2018, 14-16h Where: Niels Henrik Abels hus, room 209 Who: everybody willing to learn about &amp;ldquo;Internet of Things and Arduino&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Work along session on deep learning</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2018-10-19-workalong/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2018-10-19-workalong/</guid><description>Session leader: Ana Costa
In this session you will learn what is meant by deep-learning. Examples will be given in python and R.
Bring your laptop if you want to try it out!
When: 19th October 2018, 14h-16h Location: Niels Henrik Abels hus, room 209 Who: everybody willing to learn about deep learning</description></item><item><title>Co-working session on "The Programming Historian"</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2018-10-12-coworking/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2018-10-12-coworking/</guid><description>Session leader: Annika Rockenberger
Annika will pick a lesson from The programming Historian and give us a little intro on how programming is taught to humanities researchers.
The Programming Historian publishes novice-friendly, peer-reviewed tutorials that help humanists learn a wide range of digital tools, techniques, and workflows to facilitate research and teaching.
When: 12th October 2018, 14-16h Where: Niels Henrik Abels hus, room 209 Who: everybody willing to learn about &amp;ldquo;Programming for Humanities Researchers&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Demo session on NetworkX python package</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2018-09-21-demo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2018-09-21-demo/</guid><description>Session leader: Annika Rockenberger
NetworkX is a Python package for the creation, manipulation, and study of the structure, dynamics, and functions of complex networks.
During this Coding lightning demo session:
Learn about networkX python package Get concrete examples on how to use it Discuss your use cases For preparation you can read Complex Network Analysis in Python and the networkX documentation (https://networkx.github.io/)
When: 21st September 2018, 14-16h Location: Niels Henrik Abels hus, room 209 Who: everybody willing to learn about networkX python package</description></item><item><title>use R! group Functions, loops and list-columns - taking control of lists with purrr</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2018-09-19-user/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2018-09-19-user/</guid><description>Session leader: Dmytro Perepolkin
Are you still writing for loops? What are some of the advantages of functional programming in R? What makes a good function? How to take control of nested lists and turn chaos into order? Come and explore a fun world of {purrr} and discover hidden gems in this awesome tidyverse package. Filled with practical examples from author&amp;rsquo;s recently published packages, this talk may help you discover some of the new (and old) functions you may not have used before and encourage you on your journey to becoming a better R programmer.</description></item><item><title>Arduino Workshop</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2018-09-18-hive/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2018-09-18-hive/</guid><description>At the kick-off event, we&amp;rsquo;ll get to know each other, exchange our interests into either using some new technology like IoT, micro-electornics, or looking for interesting application and challenging settings for these technology. The goal is to come together and establish few key projects on which we can learn and collaborate across our own disciplines.
When: Tuesday 18 September, 14-18h: 14-16h flash presentations (8 min) 16-18h hands-on workshop to learn about microcontroller and sensors past 18h Pizza and socializing Where: Åpen Sone at IFI (room Ada 3407, Ole-Johan Dahls hus, Gaustadalléen 23b) Who: students, PhDs, postdocs, researchers, technicians Register here to join us for the workshop!</description></item><item><title>Book Club on Teaching Tech together</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2018-09-14-bookclub/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2018-09-14-bookclub/</guid><description>Session leader: Anne Fouilloux
We do not meet this week but we encourage you start reading and commenting Greg Wilson&amp;rsquo;s book &amp;ldquo;Teaching Tech together&amp;rdquo;.
We are using https://web.hypothes.is/, an online tool to annotate the web, with anyone, anywhere.
Start reading &amp;ldquo;Teaching Tech together&amp;rdquo; using hypothes.is at https://hypothes.is/groups/mReaNk2e/studygroup-uio.
online material to learn how to use hypothes.is:
https://web.hypothes.is/quick-start-guide-for-students/</description></item><item><title>Work along session on National data archives</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2018-09-07-workalong/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2018-09-07-workalong/</guid><description>Session leader: Michael Heeremans
More and more researchers need to make available their data before being able to publish an article in a scientific journal. During this work-along StudyGroup@ session you will get an overview of the possibilities you have to archive (long-term preservation) your data. This short demo will help you to understand how you can use the available tools.
Registration is not necessary but we ask you to come on time.</description></item><item><title>Planning of events for fall 2018</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2018-08-31-admin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2018-08-31-admin/</guid><description>Meeting to plan events and activities for fall 2018.
When: Friday 31 August, 14-15h: Where: Niels Henrik Abels hus, room 209 Who: Everybody willing to be involved in the organization of the UiO@Carpentry StudyGroup is welcome.</description></item><item><title>Informal discussion</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2018-07-12-admin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/study_group/activities/2018-07-12-admin/</guid><description>Meeting to draft a plan for UiO@Carpentry Study Group.</description></item><item><title>Software Carpentry at the University of Oslo in 2015 and 2016</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/reports/report_carpentry-uio_2015/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/reports/report_carpentry-uio_2015/</guid><description>Software Carpentry at the University of Oslo in 2015 and 2016 # Software Carpentry is a volunteer organization whose goal is to make scientists more productive, and their work more reliable, by teaching them basic computing skills. Founded in 1998, it runs short, intensive workshops that cover program design, version control, testing, and task automation.
In 2015, the (then) only two certified Software Carpentry instructors, Karin Lagesen and Lex Nederbragt, started a collaboration with the Science Library (Realfagsbilbioteket), with the goal to offer more workshops and recruit more instructors.</description></item><item><title/><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/charter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/charter/</guid><description>Carpentry@UiO Charter # This charter describes our procedures and regulations.
Organization # The Club board is made up of 6 members:
4 members elected for 2-years. 2 members are designated by the UiO Library Elections will be organized every year for renewing half of the elected members of the board (2 members).
The board will appoint a board chair, vice chair, communications officer and secretary at the first meeting of the new board after the election.</description></item><item><title/><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/members/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/members/</guid><description>Who are we? # Board # Lex Nederbragt UiO, Department of BioSciences (IBV) and Department of Informatics (IFI)
Chair Mohamed Abdelhalim UiO, Institute of Basic Medical Sciences (IMB)
Vice Chair Désirée Treichler UiO, Department of Geosciences (GEO)
Secretary Anne Schad Bergsaker UiO, University Center for Information Technology (USIT)
Outreach officer Annika Rockenberger UiO, Humanities and Social Sciences Library (UB)
Appointed by University of Oslo library Sofie Gilbert UiO, Library, Digital Scholarship Center (UB)</description></item><item><title/><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/more/code_of_conduct/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/more/code_of_conduct/</guid><description>Code of Conduct # We follow the Carpentries&amp;rsquo; Code of Conduct to provide an inclusive and supportive environment for our learners and our members. Any violation of our Code of Conduct should be reported, it will then be handled as quickly as possible and will remain confidential:
to report Code of Conduct violations for official Carpentries workshops, see the Carpentries Code of Conduct Incident Reporting Guidelines to report Code of Conduct violations for local Carpentry@UiO workshops, use UiO&amp;rsquo;s speak-up (English) or si-fra (Norwegian) reporting If the workshop is a local workshop rather than an official Carpentries workshop, the workshop website will have the Carpentry@UiO logo:</description></item><item><title/><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/reports/report_carpentry-uio_2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/reports/report_carpentry-uio_2021/</guid><description>Report Carpentry@UiO 2021 # Workshops held # Two-day Data Carpentry Workshop # November Data Carpentry: Social Sciences and Humanities Using R - on-site One-day workshops # December Carpentry: Databases and SQL - on-site November Carpentry: Plotting and Programming with Python (Novices) - on-site October Carpentry@UiO: Writing and Publishing on the Web Together Using GitHub - on-site Mini-workshops # May Carpentry@UiO Data Analysis and Visualization in R and Tidyverse (Novices) - online March Carpentry: Plotting and Programming with Python (Novices) - online January Carpentry pilot Workshop (Online): Introduction to Conda for (Data) Scientists - joint coordination by Digital Scholarship Center, CodeRefinery, Finnish Geospatial Research Institute FGI, UiT: The Arctic University of Norway and Aalto University - online In numbers # Workshop modes # Three online workshops Four on-site workshops Workshop types # One 2-day DC workshop Three 1-day Carpentry workshops (Python, SQL) One 1-day Carpentry@UiO workshop (R Tidyverse) Two half-day Carpentry@UiO workshops (GitHub, Conda) Workshop participation # Date Topic Venue Registered_Attendees Total_Registered* Show-Up 2021-12-07 SQL on-site 12 18 10 2021-11-30 Python on-site 30 73 20 2021-11-22 Data Carpentry SSH on-site 28 35 20/13 2021-11-03 GitHub on-site 12 15 4 2021-05-25 R Tidyverse online 21 56 NA 2021-03-02 Python online 52 124 NA *including all registered attendees, all on waiting list and all de-registered</description></item><item><title/><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/workshops/for_instructors/onboarding-checklist/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/workshops/for_instructors/onboarding-checklist/</guid><description>Onboarding Document # Contents of document: # Become a Carpentries certified instructor/ helper Plan a workshop Teach a workshop Overview of instructor responsibilities Overview of co-instructor/ helper responsibilities Overview of administrator responsibilities 1. Become a Carpentries certified instructor / helper # Certification # Instructor certification: Contact us at carpadmin@carpentry.uio.no and familiarize yourself withthe Carpentries Code of Conduct. Helper certification: Contact us at carpadmin@carpentry.uio.no and familiarize yourself withthe Carpentries Code of Conduct.</description></item><item><title/><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/workshops/for_instructors/workshop-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/workshops/for_instructors/workshop-guide/</guid><description>General # these checklists are in addition to the ones provided by The Carpentries for their official workshops - note that not all workshops at UiO are standard Carpentries workshops It is mandatory to use the Bcc field for sending emails to participants - that way we protect participants&amp;rsquo; privacy by not displaying email addresses to all recipients. email lists: carpadmin @ carpentry dot uio dot no &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; coordinators at the University Library and the chair person of the Carpentry@UiO Board organizers @ carpentry dot uio dot no &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; all instructors and helpers, plus those on the carpadmin list announcements @ carpentry dot uio dot no &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; all people that have shown interest or have attended workshops + those on the organizers list contact-us @ carpentry dot uio dot no&amp;ndash;&amp;gt; coordinators at the University Library.</description></item><item><title>Initiatives we like</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/more/initiatives/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/more/initiatives/</guid><description>Other groups # We list here other initiatives, ideas and programs that aims at improving programing skills of students, PhDs, postdocs and researchers.
The Carpentries # Teach foundational coding and data science skills to researchers worldwide. Join the Carpentries
NeIC CodeRefinery # Teach students and researchers how to write better code and provide research groups with software development e-infrastructure tools to collaboratively develop, review, discuss, test, and share their codes.</description></item></channel></rss>