<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Governance on Carpentry at the University of Oslo</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/</link><description>Recent content in Governance on Carpentry at the University of Oslo</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/charter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/charter/</guid><description>Carpentry@UiO Charter # This charter describes our procedures and regulations.
Organization # The Club board is made up of 6 members:
4 members elected for 2-years. 2 members are designated by the UiO Library Elections will be organized every year for renewing half of the elected members of the board (2 members).
The board will appoint a board chair, vice chair, communications officer and and secretary at the first meeting of the new board after the election.</description></item><item><title/><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/members/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/members/</guid><description>Who are we? # Board # Lex Nederbragt UiO, Department of BioSciences (IBV) and Department of Informatics (IFI)
chair Viviane Girardin Norwegian Institute for Water Research, Section for Environmental Data Science (NIVA)
vice-chair Tobias Busch UiO, Department of Special Needs Education (ISP)
secretary Anne Schad Bergsaker UiO, University Center for Information Technology (USIT) Annika Rockenberger UiO, Humanities and Social Sciences Library (UB)
appointed by University of Oslo library Aino Rinhaug UiO, Library, Science Library (UB)</description></item></channel></rss>