<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Reports on Carpentry at the University of Oslo</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/reports/</link><description>Recent content in Reports on Carpentry at the University of Oslo</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/reports/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Carpentry@UiO 2022 Annual Report</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/reports/report_carpentry-uio_2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/reports/report_carpentry-uio_2022/</guid><description>Carpentry@UiO 2022 Annual Report # Report written by Elisa Pierfederici, Sofie Gilbert and Annika Rockenberger (University of Oslo library)
Learner Feedback and Continuous Evaluation # Carpentries survey # Major strength # What to be improved # How instructors and helpers affected learning experiences # Survey in future # Workshops held # Two-day Data Carpentry Workshop # November Data Carpentry: Social Sciences and Humanities Using R - on-site September TidyVerse - on-site April Carpentry@UiO: Data Analysis and Visualization in R and Tidyverse (Novices) - on-site One-day Carpentry Workshop # November Data Carpentry: R for Social Scientist - on-site October Unix Shell - on-site April Using Databases and SQL - on-site In numbers # Workshop modes # All workshop were done in-person Workshop types # Three 2-day Carpentry workshop (R, Tidyverse, R-Tydiverse) Three 1-day Carpentry workshops (R, Unix Shell and SQL) #* Comment Elisa: I have notice there is a difference between Carpentry and Carpentry@UIO workshop but I am not sure which belong to which</description></item><item><title>Carpentry@UiO 2020 Annual Report</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/reports/report_carpentry-uio_2020/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/reports/report_carpentry-uio_2020/</guid><description>Carpentry@UiO 2020 Annual Report # Report written by Naoe Tatara and Annika Rockenberger (both University of Oslo library)
Learner Feedback and Continuous Evaluation # Carpentries survey # In this year, we used the Carpentries pre- and post-workshop survey. Due to the problems described in the next section, we have not yet gotten access to the whole dataset. However, the responses given in 5-Likert scale were mostly positive.
On the other hand, the responses written in free text are summarised in &amp;ldquo;Carpentries-survey-results&amp;rdquo; Sheet in Carpentry@UiO G Suite shared drive, which is accessible only to board members.</description></item><item><title>Carpentry@UiO 2019 Annual Report</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/reports/report_carpentry-uio_2019/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/reports/report_carpentry-uio_2019/</guid><description>Carpentry@UiO 2019 Annual Report # Learner Feedback and Continuous Evaluation # Spring Term 2019 # See the detailed report for the spring term 2019 Report Spring 2019 Fall Term 2019 # See the detailed report for 2019 incl. the feedback for the fall term 2019 Workshops # Programming with Python (novices) - Feb 8, 2019 Introduction to Version Control with Git (novices) - Feb 15, 2019 Git in Practice (intermediate) - Feb 27, 2019 Data Analysis and Visualisation in R for Ecologists - Mar 8, 2019 Unix Shell (novices) - Apr 24, 2019 Data Analysis and Visualisation in R for Ecologists - May 15, 2019 Introduction to R with Tidyverse (pt.</description></item><item><title>Carpentries-Workshops 2019 - Summary Of Learners' Feedback</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/reports/summary_feedback_uio-carpentry_2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/reports/summary_feedback_uio-carpentry_2019/</guid><description>Carpentries-Workshops 2019 &amp;ndash; Summary Of Learners&amp;rsquo; Feedback # Data and Data Analysis # After every workshop taught by Carpentry@UiO, a post-workshop feedback survey is sent out to participants, circa one-two weeks after the workshop. The responses are collected in Nettskjema. For this report, I have downloaded the data from the main Nettkjema survey as well as the data from two survey forms that were created for the GitHub workshop in September 2019 and the Databases and SQL workshop in October 2019.</description></item><item><title>Report of the Instructor Status Survey 2019</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/reports/report_instructor-status-survey_2019-11-07/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/reports/report_instructor-status-survey_2019-11-07/</guid><description>Report of the Instructor Status Survey 2019 # Author: Annika Rockenberger Date: Nov 7, 2019
Introduction # Data Collection # An online survey was created using Nettskjema (University of Oslo web-tool for surveys). The questions asked can be found in the survey document. The survey was then send to the organizers mailing list on Oct 10. A reminder to participate in the survey was sent out to the same list on Oct 16 and Nov 06.</description></item><item><title>Survey – Carpentry@UiO Instructor Status Quo</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/reports/survey_instructor-status_2019-09-26/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/reports/survey_instructor-status_2019-09-26/</guid><description>Survey – Carpentry@UiO Instructor Status Quo # Introduction and Purpose # Dear fellow Carpenter!
The Carpentry@UiO community is alive and well – a new team of coordinators from the University Library together with the Interim Board are working hard to support you in teaching workshops in the Carpentries spirit.
In order to gain a better and more up-to-date overview of who we are as a community, the Interim Board and the University Library have created a short survey about the status quo of our instructors.</description></item><item><title>Carpentries-Workshops Spring 2019 -- Summary Of Learners' Feedback</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/reports/summary_feedback_carpentries_spring_2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/reports/summary_feedback_carpentries_spring_2019/</guid><description>Carpentries-Workshops Spring 2019 &amp;ndash; Summary Of Learners&amp;rsquo; Feedback # Workshops # Workshops We Taught # Python (novices) - Feb 8, 2019 Intro to Git (novices) - Feb 15, 2019 Git in Practice (intermediate) - Feb 27, 2019 Data Analysis and Visualisation in R for Ecologists - Mar 8, 2019 Unix Shell (novices) - Apr 24, 2019 Data Analysis and Visualisation in R for Ecologists - May 15, 2019 Introduction to R with Tidyverse (pt.</description></item><item><title>Software Carpentry at the University of Oslo in 2015 and 2016</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/reports/report_carpentry-uio_2015/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/reports/report_carpentry-uio_2015/</guid><description>Software Carpentry at the University of Oslo in 2015 and 2016 # Software Carpentry is a volunteer organization whose goal is to make scientists more productive, and their work more reliable, by teaching them basic computing skills. Founded in 1998, it runs short, intensive workshops that cover program design, version control, testing, and task automation.
In 2015, the (then) only two certified Software Carpentry instructors, Karin Lagesen and Lex Nederbragt, started a collaboration with the Science Library (Realfagsbilbioteket), with the goal to offer more workshops and recruit more instructors.</description></item><item><title/><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/reports/report_carpentry-uio_2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/about/reports/report_carpentry-uio_2021/</guid><description>Report Carpentry@UiO 2021 # Workshops held # Two-day Data Carpentry Workshop # November Data Carpentry: Social Sciences and Humanities Using R - on-site One-day workshops # December Carpentry: Databases and SQL - on-site November Carpentry: Plotting and Programming with Python (Novices) - on-site October Carpentry@UiO: Writing and Publishing on the Web Together Using GitHub - on-site Mini-workshops # May Carpentry@UiO Data Analysis and Visualization in R and Tidyverse (Novices) - online March Carpentry: Plotting and Programming with Python (Novices) - online January Carpentry pilot Workshop (Online): Introduction to Conda for (Data) Scientists - joint coordination by Digital Scholarship Center, CodeRefinery, Finnish Geospatial Research Institute FGI, UiT: The Arctic University of Norway and Aalto University - online In numbers # Workshop modes # Three online workshops Four on-site workshops Workshop types # One 2-day DC workshop Three 1-day Carpentry workshops (Python, SQL) One 1-day Carpentry@UiO workshop (R Tidyverse) Two half-day Carpentry@UiO workshops (GitHub, Conda) Workshop participation # Date Topic Venue Registered_Attendees Total_Registered* Show-Up 2021-12-07 SQL on-site 12 18 10 2021-11-30 Python on-site 30 73 20 2021-11-22 Data Carpentry SSH on-site 28 35 20/13 2021-11-03 GitHub on-site 12 15 4 2021-05-25 R Tidyverse online 21 56 NA 2021-03-02 Python online 52 124 NA *including all registered attendees, all on waiting list and all de-registered</description></item></channel></rss>