<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mores on Carpentry at the University of Oslo</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/more/</link><description>Recent content in Mores on Carpentry at the University of Oslo</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https:uio-carpentry.github.io/more/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/more/code_of_conduct/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/more/code_of_conduct/</guid><description>Code of Conduct # We follow the Carpentries&amp;rsquo; Code of Conduct to provide an inclusive and supportive environment for our learners and our members. Any violation of our Code of Conduct should be reported, it will then be handled as quickly as possible and will remain confidential:
to report Code of Conduct violations for official Carpentries workshops, see the Carpentries Code of Conduct Incident Reporting Guidelines to report Code of Conduct violations for local Carpentry@UiO workshops, use UiO&amp;rsquo;s speak-up (English) or si-fra (Norwegian) reporting If the workshop is a local workshop rather than an official Carpentries workshop, the workshop website will have the Carpentry@UiO logo:</description></item><item><title>Initiatives we like</title><link>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/more/initiatives/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https:uio-carpentry.github.io/more/initiatives/</guid><description>Other groups # We list here other initiatives, ideas and programs that aims at improving programing skills of students, PhDs, postdocs and researchers.
The Carpentries # Teach foundational coding and data science skills to researchers worldwide. Join the Carpentries
NeIC CodeRefinery # Teach students and researchers how to write better code and provide research groups with software development e-infrastructure tools to collaboratively develop, review, discuss, test, and share their codes.</description></item></channel></rss>